<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!-- This is a WordPress eXtended RSS file generated by WordPress as an export of your site. -->
<!-- It contains information about your site's posts, pages, comments, categories, and other content. -->
<!-- You may use this file to transfer that content from one site to another. -->
<!-- This file is not intended to serve as a complete backup of your site. -->

<!-- To import this information into a WordPress site follow these steps: -->
<!-- 1. Log in to that site as an administrator. -->
<!-- 2. Go to Tools: Import in the WordPress admin panel. -->
<!-- 3. Install the "WordPress" importer from the list. -->
<!-- 4. Activate & Run Importer. -->
<!-- 5. Upload this file using the form provided on that page. -->
<!-- 6. You will first be asked to map the authors in this export file to users -->
<!--    on the site. For each author, you may choose to map to an -->
<!--    existing user on the site or to create a new user. -->
<!-- 7. WordPress will then import each of the posts, pages, comments, categories, etc. -->
<!--    contained in this file into your site. -->

<!-- generator="WordPress/4.2.5" created="2015-10-13 23:45" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:excerpt="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/excerpt/"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:wp="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/"
>

<channel>
	<title>Blog of Vikash Loomba</title>
	<link>http://vikashloomba.com/blog</link>
	<description>My ideas, thoughts, and experiences.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2015 23:45:25 +0000</pubDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<wp:wxr_version>1.2</wp:wxr_version>
	<wp:base_site_url>http://vikashloomba.com/blog</wp:base_site_url>
	<wp:base_blog_url>http://vikashloomba.com/blog</wp:base_blog_url>

	<wp:author><wp:author_id>1</wp:author_id><wp:author_login>vikash</wp:author_login><wp:author_email>me@vikashloomba.com</wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[vikash]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>


	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=4.2.5</generator>

	<item>
		<title>Coding Dojo Week 0 - Prework - Entry 1</title>
		<link>http://vikashloomba.com/blog/index.php/2015/06/17/coding-dojo-week-0-prework-entry-1/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 20:44:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vikash]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vikashloomba.com/blog/?p=10</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[When I signed up for the Coding Dojo back in May, I didn't necessarily know what I wanted out of it. As a 19-year old college student, I've heard every reason as to why completing college is important. I signed up for the Coding Dojo Summer Session primarily because it gives me flexibility. Depending on my experiences, I could either pursue work full-time or use my newfound knowledge to help me pursue my degree in Informatics and potentially start a side-business. Now with the Dojo starting next week, I am trying to anticipate which way it will go, but I want to document my experiences along the way.

I have now started the pre-coursework for the Dojo. Being a student, I didn't get much time to finish much of the pre-coursework prior to this week. With my quarter now over, and the Dojo starting in less than seven days, I'm hunkering down and attempting to finish the 50 hours of coursework before I start.

As a little bit of discretion, I do have some previous CS knowledge. I have taken an introductory Java class, which has helped immensely in preventing me from starting from square one with the pre-coursework. Just as I read many times online, once you learn the basics of programming, switching between languages isn't too hard. All I needed to do was familiarize myself with JS syntax, but the actual problem solving stays nearly identical.

In the time of writing this, I've completed the Midterm and will be moving on to the "Advanced Coursework". I am extremely eager for the actual Dojo to begin, and I can't wait to see my own progress through this 12 week journey!

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>10</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2015-06-17 20:44:48</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2015-06-17 20:44:48</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>coding-dojo-week-0-prework-entry-1</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="coding-dojo"><![CDATA[Coding Dojo]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="programming"><![CDATA[Programming]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>The Dilemma of Higher Education in America</title>
		<link>http://vikashloomba.com/blog/index.php/2015/06/17/the-dilemma-of-higher-education-in-america/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 21:44:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vikash]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vikashloomba.com/blog/?p=12</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="graf--p">Growing up, arguably the number one piece of educational advice that I most received was “Go to college”. This is a sentiment that many of my peers agree with as well. This one simple line was drilled constantly throughout my high school years. In fact, it is drilled in to our heads so much that many high school students don’t consider any other option as a viable alternative. But does that mean this advice is wrong?</p>
<p class="graf--p">In the past couple of decades, we have seen the cost of a college education rise exponentially. What used to be affordable for a middle-class family is no longer, but the expectation for attending has noticeably increased. In our modern economy, the primary benefit to attending college seems simple; to get a job. It is a means to an end (with the right degree).</p>
<p class="graf--p">Now, before I continue, I want to address another commonly-used argument for attending college; the people you meet and the experiences you make will develop you as a person in ways that other options can't provide. I both agree and disagree with this statement, depending on the person. "Experiences" is a subjective term, simply because we all experience things differently. If a group of people share an experience, lets say bungee-jumping, each one of them is going to experience it in a different way. The experience of bungee-jumping of any individual in the group is a cumulation of all their previous experiences up to that point.</p>
<p class="graf--p">Like I mentioned earlier, the "value" of college for many (if not most) people is to get a job. But, as we've seen, with more and more of the population graduating with degrees, the overall value of a Bachelor's degree has fallen. The concept isn't new, and many of us know this. Many people continue to attend college, but their experiences are not necessarily leading them to a job. The obvious question that I have continually asked myself  is “What if I can reach the same end with different means?”.</p>
<p class="graf--p">Traditionally, the alternative to a college education are trade-schools. Many trade-schools offer subsidized tuition and generally are less than 4 years. However, the subsequent jobs one can pursue are extremely limited in their overall scope, due to the specialized nature of the training. College is unique in the sense that it teaches students a little bit of a lot of different things. It can, in theory, prepare oneself for a variety of different jobs in different fields (In practice, this is generally far from true). The question remains then, <strong>why is there no obvious alternative?</strong></p>
<p class="graf--p">Programs like coding bootcamps are filling that void in a niche field that is in high demand, but I feel that other fields need similar crash courses to offer to students who know what they want to do. As someone who was in that boat all throughout high school, programs like Coding Dojo are amazing because it allows me to learn just what I want to learn. That in itself is valuable, because I am not wasting my time worrying about grades in other classes that might be irrelevant. It cuts away the fat and gives you just what you need to know.</p>
<p class="graf--p">I think we need more and more programs like this. Programs that prepare students for a certain type of job, and then gives them extensive resources to land a job. What I would personally like to see is companies who might sponsor such programs, and then hire those who passed. Many jobs could utilize this approach, as it benefits both employers and job-seekers.</p>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>12</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2015-06-17 21:44:43</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2015-06-17 21:44:43</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>the-dilemma-of-higher-education-in-america</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="coding-dojo"><![CDATA[Coding Dojo]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="editorial"><![CDATA[Editorial]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Why I Think Programming Is Tough To Learn</title>
		<link>http://vikashloomba.com/blog/index.php/2015/06/18/why-i-think-programming-is-tough-to-learn/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 22:46:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vikash]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vikashloomba.com/blog/?p=15</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Learning any new skill is hard. It requires patience, time, and plenty of motivation. For a lot of people, these three things are very present, but programming is still extremely hard to learn. I have a theory as to why.

The process of learning is complicated, and varies depending on what exactly you are learning. For most skills, you need to buy something to actually learn. For example, to learn guitar, you need a guitar. To learn to snowboard, well, you need a snowboard (among other things). With programming, this barrier to entry is seemingly lowered, because everyone has a computer. Unfortunately, it doesn't make learning any easier.

You can track your progress with relative ease when learning most things. With guitars, it might be finally playing that chord right, with snowboarding, it might be finishing the run without falling. These are physical, trackable things that do something important psychologically; it helps you build learning momentum. When the three conditions that I mentioned earlier are present, in addition to momentum, learning becomes considerably more engaging, fun, and easy. For many skills, building momentum comes after learning a little bit of the basics. Once you have that, you can start to build momentum and make considerable progress on the learning curve.

So why is programming any different?

I think programming is different for a variety of reasons, and I want to touch upon the most important of those reasons.

<strong>1. Expectations</strong>

We live in the age of technology, and we have seen how simple technologies can become viral and change various aspects of our lives. In addition to that, we have seen the creators of these technologies become rich, at seemingly any age. It doesn't matter if you're 13 or 50, knowing how to program <em>seems </em>like it could make anyone wealthy.

Unfortunately, not all of us will become the next Mark Zuckerberg or Bill Gates. In fact, very few ever do.

Having these expectations can seriously hamper your momentum when trying to learn how to program. You should learn programming because you enjoy learning it.

<strong>2. Getting the "basics"</strong>

With most skills, the basics are exactly what they seem, basic. Learning them isn't extremely difficult and once you do get them down the learning process becomes a lot more enjoyable. With programming, the fundamentals are simply more difficult to grasp. Programming has everything to do with how you <strong>think </strong>and not what you can <strong>physically </strong>do. I bolded "think" and "physically" because they both are two very different kinds of skills. Learning how to think in a different way is much more complicated than trying to learn how to do something different physically.

This is why many people associate good math skills to programming. Once you learn and understand basic pre-calculus and calculus concepts, programming does become easier, as it is something that I can attest to. Those concepts you learn in math are difficult because they force you to think about something different, and the only way to actually understand it is to change your frame of thought. In math, when you get the answer to a question wrong that you just can't figure out, the problem almost always lies in how you were thinking about the problem. Once you are able to change your frame of thought, you almost always think "sheesh that was easy if I had just thought about it differently". Once you can do this sort of thinking, learning to program becomes a lot easier.

<strong>3. Getting Results</strong>

The last, and personally the most critical reason why programming is hard to learn, is that it is hard to get really good results early. Now, for most skills, even when you are just starting out, you might have beginners luck or maybe through some fluke you do really good on some occasion. Going back to the guitar example, you might somehow play really good while practicing once, or if you're snowboarding you might get some really good runs in where you didn't fall at all.

These events, or flukes, or whatever you might call it, help immensely in building momentum. It's like getting a taste of what you are capable of. And best of all, for many skills this can happen early on. With programming, this point is harder to reach. It takes longer for an event like this, and because of that you don't have the same momentum, comparatively.

Going beyond this, building momentum and getting results with programming is also difficult because there is often a lack of creativity in the beginning stages. Whether it be books or online tutorials, <strong>it's hard to emulate a result with programming without</strong> <strong>"copying"</strong>. <strong> </strong>This, of course, only applies to the beginning stages. But, it is still quite different from other skills, where you might early on develop different mechanisms or styles that aid you in your learning.

So this leads us the most important part; <strong>how can I make learning to program easier for myself?</strong>

Although there is no easy answer, I think a couple of different different tools are available that can make this process easier. One of my favorites is <a href="http://www.arduino.cc" target="_blank">Arduino</a>, a development platform that uses programming in conjunction with a piece of hardware to produce some sort of result. You can buy one of their boards and program it to do something. The primary benefit that I have gotten from it is that it helps build a lot of momentum. Your expectations automatically conform to what you see, which is a small board that seemingly cannot do much. But when you start to program small things, you eventually start getting ideas as to what you can do with the little you've been given. This creativity aids in the momentum process and allows you to explore and learn yourself. Although this is just one tool, there are others like Raspberry Pi which offer the same sort of experience.

To conclude, we know now that programming is no easy task, but it CAN be learned with the right mix of variables. Having hardware you can program aids in this process and allows you to build momentum at a rate more comparable to learning other skills. Once you are able to change how you approach a problem, and get just the right amount of basics down, programming can be just as fun as other skills. Your approach to it is everything.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>15</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2015-06-18 22:46:39</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2015-06-18 22:46:39</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>why-i-think-programming-is-tough-to-learn</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="editorial"><![CDATA[Editorial]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="programming"><![CDATA[Programming]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Coding Dojo Week 1 - HTML/CSS/MySQL - Entry 2</title>
		<link>http://vikashloomba.com/blog/index.php/2015/06/28/coding-dojo-week-1-htmlcssmysql-entry-2/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 02:56:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vikash]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vikashloomba.com/blog/?p=20</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[If I had two words to describe my first week at the Dojo it would probably be "Holy Shit". Our first week was filled with tons of learning, accompanied by an equal if not greater level of frustration, all topped with unprecedented levels of accomplishment.

This first week of the Dojo has brought together all my bits of knowledge of HTML, CSS, databases, and more. Most of these concepts I had explored all throughout high school, but I never really connected them and dove in to them in such detail. The result was me learning more than I possibly ever thought I could learn in an educational environment. I am literally amazed at how much progress I - and everyone else - have made in just a week. Throughout high school and college I have always had a hard time being engaged, due to my ADD. This is the first time I feel I am engaged in my work for long periods of time while actually enjoying the fruits of my labor.

<hr />

&nbsp;

This week, we primarily did HTML/CSS work. Our main assignments were to recreate websites or templates from scratch, without the use of any framework or pre-made CSS/HTML. I struggled for the first half of the week, but I managed to get a hang of everything by the end. On Friday we took our first certification test, and I managed to pass, which was nice. We ended the week with database design, something I dabbled in while learning the basics of Ruby on Rails, so I felt a little more at home and was able to grasp the concepts with relative ease. I am excited to incorporate our databases with PHP and create dynamic web pages, which we will start next week.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>20</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2015-06-28 02:56:01</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2015-06-28 02:56:01</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>coding-dojo-week-1-htmlcssmysql-entry-2</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="coding-dojo"><![CDATA[Coding Dojo]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="programming"><![CDATA[Programming]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Coding Dojo Update - LAMP and Beyond</title>
		<link>http://vikashloomba.com/blog/index.php/2015/08/17/coding-dojo-update-lamp-and-beyond/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 05:04:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vikash]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vikashloomba.com/blog/?p=23</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Hey readers,

This update is quite late in its release due primarily to laziness on my behalf. With that being said, I have been extraordinarily busy with the bootcamp since my last update that I posted.

So far, the journey has been nothing short of incredible.

In the ending of my last update I detailed that we would be beginning to create dynamic web pages using PHP, but more broadly, the LAMP stack. Since writing that update, we have not only completed the LAMP stack (Linux, Apache, MySQL, PHP), but also the MEAN stack (MongoDB, Express, AngularJS, NodeJS) having just taken the Black belt for MEAN on August 14, 2015.

The primary things that happened in between my updates were:
<ul>
	<li>Taking the Red Belt exam for LAMP stack. I passed with a score of 9.5/10.</li>
	<li>Doing the LAMP stack project week. I partnered up with two of my buddies and created <a href="https://github.com/VikashLoomba/GreenSpace" target="_blank">GreenSpace</a>, an open-source reservation platform for Marijuana retail shops and Medical Dispensaries.</li>
	<li>After project week, we began delving deep in to Javascript, learning the ins and outs of concepts such as callbacks.</li>
	<li>We then began NodeJS, slowly incorporating the rest of the MEAN stack in as well.</li>
	<li>After completing the MEAN stack, we took the Black Belt exam for it last week Friday.</li>
</ul>
That is the summarized rundown of what has happened since then. The Black Belt exam was difficult, and there is a solid chance I didn't pass it this first time through. I understand all of the back-end logic and was getting all my data passed through to the front end correctly, but I wasn't able to get it to display correctly. If I do end up passing, it is because I showed in my code that I was able to get most of the back-end logic correct, and my problems were primarily in the front-end (functionality takes precedence in grading).

<strong>What's to come?</strong>

Next week, we start project week for the MEAN stack, which means I will have to hunker down for some long days. My idea right now is creating a classfields web-app for college campuses. Right now I am leaning towards building this so I can use the REST API I create for the backend to help create other apps for college students that can take advantage of the login API. This way, I can expand in to creating other applications using such data.

After project week, we are given a choice to either continue on with the standard three stacks and finish with Ruby on Rails, or we can choose to learn iOS app development. The iOS course was just recently finished after a very successful pilot, according to the Dojo's founder, Michael Choi. HE described it as the best course to date, and I want to take full advantage of it. I am especially excited for iOS development because mobile programming would be a great skill to have under my belt. Now that I can build a solid CRUD application in the MEAN and LAMP stacks, mobile seems like the next progression. My ultimate goal is to have a skill set that allows me to combines my knowledge of desktop development (front and back-end) and mobile development and create a full suite of applications that work with each other with a REST API powering the data between them all. I could imagine this is a powerful combination, not only from a development standpoint, but also for potential employers recognizing the breadth of knowledge (with depth varying for each technology).

<strong>To conclude,</strong>

I have just over a month left at the Dojo and I want to make the most out of it that I can. The amount I've learned is insane, and I only want to keep this momentum going further. I've seen people burn out all around me, but I think keeping a manageable balance of sanity and work/learning is the key to being successful here. I'll hopefully be back soon for another update.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>23</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2015-08-17 05:04:56</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2015-08-17 05:04:56</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>coding-dojo-update-lamp-and-beyond</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="coding-dojo"><![CDATA[Coding Dojo]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="programming"><![CDATA[Programming]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Coding Dojo Update - Black Belt Completed</title>
		<link>http://vikashloomba.com/blog/index.php/2015/08/19/coding-dojo-update-black-belt-completed/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 03:08:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vikash]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vikashloomba.com/blog/?p=25</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Hey readers,

Yesterday I found out that I passed the black belt. Not only was it a huge relief, but an accomplishment that really shows how far this bootcamp will take you in a short amount of time. With that being said, there is still a whole other course to get through before the end of the program (iOS Swift, can't wait!!!).

Some details on the black belt:
<ul>
	<li>It was 5 hours long. It went by in what seemed like 2 hours.</li>
	<li>The basic requirements were implementing a user login, backend REST API, basic CRUD operations, as well as embedded documents.</li>
	<li>I passed with a 8.75/10</li>
</ul>
For readers who might join the Dojo or are a part of it but haven't gotten to the MEAN black belt, take another look at bullet point two. If you can do those things in the MEAN stack, you're chances of passing go up exponentially.

I ended up with an 8.75 due to a not-so-functional user registration and lack of validations. I think in the end the most important functionality was getting the RESTful API sending data back and forth properly. It really is the core of the application, so if you can build one confidently then don't be too nervous.

Now we are on to project week. I've had a really difficult time deciding what I wanted to pursue, but I've ended up on making a User Dashboard application. Right now I've set up very basic login/registration functionality, but the next (and hardest part) will be incorporating various API's as data sources to display on the dashboard. Although most API's are relatively easy to work with and pull data from, social API's seem to go up in their level of difficulty to use, due to complexities in verifying the identity. I may pivot and decide on another project, but I'll see where this takes me.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>25</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2015-08-19 03:08:33</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2015-08-19 03:08:33</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>coding-dojo-update-black-belt-completed</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="coding-dojo"><![CDATA[Coding Dojo]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="editorial"><![CDATA[Editorial]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="programming"><![CDATA[Programming]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>iOS &amp; Swift Development - Coding Dojo Update</title>
		<link>http://vikashloomba.com/blog/?p=29</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov -0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vikash]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vikashloomba.com/blog/?p=29</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[These last two weeks were the official start of the iOS course that I talked about in my last post.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>29</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2015-09-03 02:51:15</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>draft</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
